const e=[{id:1,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Tilde",question:"What does the `~` symbol in the terminal prompt represent?",options:["the root directory","the user's home directory","the current working directory","the system hostname","this symbol is not valid"],random:!0,answer:"the user's home directory"},{id:2,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Cash money",question:"What does the `$` at the end of the prompt indicate?",options:["the user is an administrator","the user is a guest","the user is not an administrative user","the shell is in safe mode"],random:!0,answer:"the user is not an administrative user"},{id:3,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Kitty cat",question:"In the command `cat secret_file`, what does `secret file` represent?",options:["the program name","a command option","an argument to the program","the shell type"],random:!0,answer:"an argument to the program",description:"It represents the argument, or parameter, to the program"},{id:4,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"-not sure",question:"What does the `-n` argument do in the command `echo -n Hi Everybody!!`?",options:["prints the output in bold","adds a newline","prevents echo from printing a newline at the end","prints the output in uppercase","prints the output twice"],random:!0,answer:"prevents echo from printing a newline at the end"},{id:5,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Who am I?",question:"What does the command `whoami` do?",options:["prints the hostname","prints the current directory","prints the username","prints the shell type"],random:!0,answer:"prints the username"},{id:6,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Slash of the Titans",question:"What does the `/` symbol in the terminal prompt represent?",options:["the root directory","the user's home directory","the current working directory","the system hostname","this symbol is not valid"],random:!0,answer:"the root directory"},{id:7,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Back, back, back...",question:"What does the `\\` symbol in the terminal prompt represent?",options:["the root directory","the user's home directory","the current working directory","the system hostname","this symbol is not valid"],random:!0,answer:"this symbol is not valid"},{id:8,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Root awakening",question:"What is the root directory in Linux?",options:["`/root`","`/home`","`/`","`C:\\`"],random:!0,answer:"`/`",description:"If you chose `C:\\` in the Linux section just leave my friend, you ain't gonna make it. "},{id:9,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Temporary question",question:"Which directory contains temporary data storage?",options:["`/`","`/usr`","`/usr/bin`","`/usr/lib`","`/usr/share`","`/etc`","`/var`","`/home`","`/proc`","`/tmp`"],random:!0,answer:"`/tmp`"},{id:10,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Hidden files",question:"In Linux, which character at the beginning of a filename makes the file hidden by default?",options:["`~`","`.`","`/`","`#`","`-`","`@`"],random:!0,answer:"`.`",description:"Files and directories that start with a dot `.` are hidden by default in Linux. You can view them with the `ls -a` command."},{id:11,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Biblioteca",question:"Which directory contains shared libraries for use by programs on the computer?",options:["`/`","`/usr`","`/usr/bin`","`/usr/lib`","`/usr/share`","`/etc`","`/var`","`/home`","`/proc`","`/tmp`"],random:!0,answer:"`/usr/lib`"},{id:12,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Where am I?",question:"Which command shows your current working directory?",options:["`ls`","`cd`","`pwd`","`whoami`"],random:!0,answer:"`pwd`",description:"`pwd` - present working directory"},{id:13,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"All system files",question:"Which directory contains all the system files?",options:["`/`","`/usr`","`/usr/bin`","`/usr/lib`","`/usr/share`","`/etc`","`/var`","`/home`","`/proc`","`/tmp`"],random:!0,answer:"`/usr`",description:"`usr` - unix system resource"},{id:14,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Los Santos",question:"What is the purpose of the `ls` command?",options:["change directories","list files in a directory","show system processes","display user information"],random:!0,answer:"list files in a directory"},{id:15,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"No relativity",question:"Which of the following is an absolute path?",options:["`usr/bin`","`/home/username`","`./flags`","`../tmp`"],random:!0,answer:"`/home/username`"},{id:16,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"User data",question:"Which directory contains user-owned data?",options:["`/`","`/usr`","`/usr/bin`","`/usr/lib`","`/usr/share`","`/etc`","`/var`","`/home`","`/proc`","`/tmp`"],random:!0,answer:"`/home`"},{id:17,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Where to?",question:"What does the command `cd` do when used with no arguments?",options:["changes to the root directory","changes to the previous directory","changes to the user's home directory","does nothing"],random:!0,answer:"changes to the user's home directory"},{id:18,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Here or there",question:"What does the `..` symbol mean in a file path?",options:["current directory","home directory","parent directory","root directory"],random:!0,answer:"parent directory"},{id:19,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Log Hard",question:"Which directory contains logs and caches?",options:["`/`","`/usr`","`/usr/bin`","`/usr/lib`","`/usr/share`","`/etc`","`/var`","`/home`","`/proc`","`/tmp`"],random:!0,answer:"`/var`"},{id:20,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"program_name",question:"Why do you need to type `./program_name` to run a program in the current directory on Linux, instead of just typing `program_name`?",options:["for security","to list files","to change directories","to show hidden files"],random:!0,answer:"for security",description:"By default, when you type a command in Linux, the shell searches for the command in directories listed in your `PATH` environment variable (usually system directories like `/bin`). It *does not* search the current directory for executables unless you explicitly specify it with `./`.\n\nThis prevents accidental execution of a program in your current directory that might have the same name as a trusted system command.\n\nFor example, if you downloaded a file named `ls` and run `ls`, you would just list whatever was in the directory. To actually run it would require `./ls`.\n\nTo run a program in your current directory, you must use `./`."},{id:21,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Process: Impossible",question:"Which directory contains runtime process data?",options:["`/`","`/usr`","`/usr/bin`","`/usr/lib`","`/usr/share`","`/etc`","`/var`","`/home`","`/proc`","`/tmp`"],random:!0,answer:"`/proc`"},{id:22,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Execution time",question:"Which directory contains executable files for programs installed on the computer?",options:["`/`","`/usr`","`/usr/bin`","`/usr/lib`","`/usr/share`","`/etc`","`/var`","`/home`","`/proc`","`/tmp`"],random:!0,answer:"`/usr/bin`"},{id:23,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Art attack",question:"Which directory contains program resources such as icons and art assets?",options:["`/`","`/usr`","`/usr/bin`","`/usr/lib`","`/usr/share`","`/etc`","`/var`","`/home`","`/proc`","`/tmp`"],random:!0,answer:"`/usr/share`"},{id:24,type:"radio",category:"linux",subcategory:"",title:"Configuration Wars",question:"Which directory contains system configurations?",options:["`/`","`/usr`","`/usr/bin`","`/usr/lib`","`/usr/share`","`/etc`","`/var`","`/home`","`/proc`","`/tmp`"],random:!0,answer:"`/etc`"}];export{e as default};
